m -96 -22 l -96 26 l 96 26 l 96 -22
R3官方中字
双语制作 薛定谔的加菲猫
哥谭市是我的家
Gotham City, my city.
很早以前 我独自一人
Long ago I began my one-man crusade
保护哥谭市免于犯罪和邪恶 然后罗宾也加入了
to protect her from crime and injustice and then along came Robin.
哥谭市银行
我们是正义的一方
Together we were a dynamic duo of justice
对抗哥谭市的邪恶势力 直到小罗宾长大
defending Gotham from villainous rogues until young Robin grew up.
他称自己为夜翼 独立在哥谭市打击犯罪
He took the name Nightwing and set out to fight crime on his own in Gotham.
但是罗宾的故事不会因此结束
But that wasn't the end of Robin's story.
新的罗宾很快就会加入
A new Robin would soon join our ranks,
强化我们的阵容
strengthening our team and extending the reach
并且扩展我们想要保护的正义力量
of our protective cloak of justice
打击在哥谭市的每一个黑暗角落
over every dark corner of our beloved Gotham City.
DC漫画超级英雄
乐高正义联盟：哥谭大越狱
超人
蝙蝠侠
神奇女侠
钢骨
局长别担心 蝙蝠侠和罗宾已经接手了
Don't worry, Commissioner. Batman and Robin are on the case!
谢谢你 蝙蝠侠
Thank you, Batman!
因为这些哥谭市的小混混
With Gotham's vilest villains on the loose,
也好让大家知道 哥谭市是有你们这样的…
it's good to know our city is in the capable hands of heroes like...
英雄
You two?
又不见了
Gone again.
就这些了 这些是珍贵的宝石
That's it. The last of the precious stones.
剩下的那些只是些次等品
The rest of them are only semi-precious stones.
根本不值得我们花时间去偷
Not even worth the time it'd take us to steal them.
说到时间 小企鹅 相信你会有很多时间的
Time, Penguin, is the one thing you'll have plenty of
等你回到阿卡姆疯人院的小房间后
once you're back in your cell at Arkham Asylum.
但是 首先我们来看看 你待在新的磁蝠铁笼的样子吧
But first, let's see how you fit in my new Bat-magnet cage.
正中红心 我是说正中企鹅
Bull's-eye! I mean, Penguin's-eye!
罗宾 射得好
Good shot, Robin.
在警察来之前 应该可以关住他一阵子
That should keep him grounded until the police arrive.
这就是为什么我喜欢当司机
And that's the reason I'm always the designated driver.
再见啦 企鹅
Ta-ta, Pengie!
你等等也会一起回去阿卡姆 哈莉
You'll be catching a ride back to Arkham together, Harley.
低碳出行是环保的关键
Carpooling is vital to a healthy environment.
嘿 小心开车
Hey, watch where you're driving!
我不是在说你 蝙蝠侠 你最棒了
Not you, Batman, you're good.
可怜的蝙蝠侠 你抓不到我的
Poor Batman, you'll never catch me.
加农炮
也许你可以抓些鱼
But maybe you'll catch a fish.
就像瓮中捉鳖一样简单 喔不 根本不需要瓮
Like shooting fish in a barrel... Without the barrel.
哈莉 放弃吧
Give it up, Harley!
你因偷窃 收受赃物
You're wanted for grand theft, receiving stolen goods
以及邪恶的技俩被通缉了
and egregious prop comedy.
蝙蝠侠怎么啦 要来点香蕉吗
What's the matter, Batman? My jokes driving you bananas?
被香蕉摆了一道
Betrayed by my own bananas.
蝙蝠侠 我想我找到帮手了
I may be going out on a limb here, Batman.
不对 我已经在帮手手上了
No, wait! I'm definitely going out on a limb!
哈莉 你迟到了
You're late, Harl.
不好意思 哥谭市的交通让人发疯
Sorry, traffic in Gotham will drive you batty.
毒藤女
Poison Ivy.
罗宾 离她远一点
Keep your distance from her, Robin.
不过就是一些普通的珠宝窃贼 不是吗
Associating with common jewel thieves now, are we?
普通的
"Common"?
我的健康植物四处都可以生长得很茂盛喔 蝙蝠侠
My share of the gems will go to ensuring the well-being of plants everywhere, Batman.
你爱植物的心掩盖不了你丑恶的罪行
A green thumb doesn't make up for your black heart.
除草剂 谁会带除草剂出门啊
Weed killer? Who carries weed killer?
蝙蝠侠
The Batman.
还有罗宾
And also the Robin.
我的宝贝们
My babies!
也许去阿卡姆一趟可以治治你的偏差行为
Perhaps another trip to Arkham will teach you the error of your ways.
新叶子就会长出来啰
And help you turn over a new leaf.
罗宾 看好这两个 等到相关单位来处理
Robin, cover these two until the authorities arrive.
看来还有漏网之鱼
Looks like there's one last villain to wrangle.
看来计划要成功了
I love it when a plan comes together.
嘿 你看
Hey, look at that!
酷
Whoa, cool!
在哥谭市搭公车是要付钱的
In Gotham, everybody pays bus fare.
你的动作还真是敏捷啊
Aren't you the agile one?
什么 蝙蝠侠 怎么可能
What? Batman! But how?
其实还蛮简单的
Quite simple, really.
你逃跑时已经预想了我的每一个动作
You uncannily anticipated my every move as you fled.
而我也预想了你预想了我的动作
I simply anticipated you anticipating my every move
照这样想来 我只要在不会追你的地方等你就好了
and adjusted accordingly, beating you to the place I would've chased you to.
真是让人印象深刻
Impressive.
也不用这么惊讶吧 夜翼
You shouldn't be too surprised, Nightwing!
你是怎么…
Aw. How did you...
我猜是我敏捷的身手泄漏了身份吧
Oh, I bet it was my circus aerialist moves that gave me away, right?
那些特殊技巧 也只有我会教你
As well as a few special moves that only I could have taught you.
而且呢 我也猜得到你如此大费周章的原因
Furthermore, I have deduced the reason for your theatrical game of tag.
因为今天是蝙蝠侠第一次出现的纪念日
As today marks the anniversary of the first appearance of the Batman,
又因为大部分的英雄都是感性又念旧
and as most superheroes are a highly emotional, sentimental lot,
你一定是要带我来这地方
you have obviously lured me to this location
帮我举办一个惊喜派对
to set me up for some kind of surprise party.
蝙蝠日快乐
惊喜
Surprise.
一点都不惊喜
You shouldn't have.
我真是不敢相信 他又猜到了我们的计划
I can't believe he guessed our plan. Again!
你知道吗 蝙蝠侠 这样会剥夺身为你朋友的乐趣
You know, Batman, you take the fun out of being your friend sometimes.
为什么
How so?
蝙蝠日快乐 蝙蝠侠
Happy Bat-Birthday, Batman!
看出来我的用心吗
You see what I did there?
因为你很爱秀"蝙蝠洞"和"蝙蝠车"
Because you put "bat" before "mobile" and "cave"?
其他的人也想来啦 但是都有任务在身 嘿 你看
The rest of the League wanted to be here, but duty calls. Hey, look!
大部分的少年泰坦都来了
Most of the Teen Titans showed up!
喝奶昔比赛开始
Milkshake-consuming contest begin!
- 我赢了 - 哦
- I win! - Aw.
我知道了
So I see.
生日快乐 布鲁斯
Happy anniversary, Bruce.
哥谭市的犯罪率很难让我开心 戴安娜
It's hardly happy for the criminals of Gotham City, Diana.
我是要说 谢谢你
I mean, thank you.
我知道你不想要礼物
So, I know you don't want presents,
但是罗宾 夜翼 我还有大家 都想表示点心意
but Robin, Nightwing and I all chipped in and got you something,
这真的蛮难的
which is not easy,
因为要买礼物给一个什么都有的男人
because what do you buy for a guy who literally has one of everything?
蝙蝠女 其实他也并不是什么都有
Batgirl, he can't literally have one of everything.
那倒是真的 我调查过蝙蝠洞 有些东西他居然有两个
That's true. I've inventoried the Batcave, there are some things he has two of.
嘿 你真的太有钱了
Boy, you are rich. Am I in your will?
然后我们就想到 我们可以买给你一个
Anyway, we realized there's not some thing we can buy you
你无法买来的东西
that you can't buy for yourself.
所以 你的礼物真的超棒的
So, your present is something even better.
就是跟我们在一起出去
Quality time with us!
你是说我们一起去度假
You're suggesting we take a vacation?
厉害了吧
Surprise!
非常的有想法
Very thoughtful.
不巧的是 罪犯是不会放假的
Unfortunately, crime doesn't take vacations.
哥谭市需要我
Gotham needs me.
嗯 话是这样说没错
Well, of course it does!
但是你需要休息 而我很愿意帮你照顾
But you need a break, and I'll be happy to babysit your fair...
你心爱的城市 在你不在的时候
Fair-ish city while you're gone.
我不知道耶
I don't know.
哥谭市的坏蛋 跟你之前遇过的不太一样
The villains in Gotham are a bit different than the ones you're used to.
当然不一样
Well, sure, they're different.
但是有件事我很肯定 他们都没有超能力
For one thing, most of them don't even have superpowers.
所以我想对我来说 应该不会太麻烦
I don't think they'll be too big a problem for me.
不要小看哥谭市的…
Don't underestimate Gotham's...
布鲁斯 克拉克可以处理的
Bruce, Clark really can handle it.
正义联盟的其他人 也都随时听候差遣
And the rest of the Justice League is only a phone call away.
拜托 蝙蝠侠
Oh, come on, Batman!
如果说世界上的英雄里最需要度假的
If there is one hero in this world that deserves and needs a vacay,
那个人一定是你
it is definitely you.
- 好吧 - 什么 你答应了吗
- Fine. - What? You'll do it?
他当然是答应了
Of course he said the yes.
有谁能够拒绝夜翼楚楚可怜的眼神呢
How could one say no to Nightwing's dreamy eyes of the puppy dog?
我只能说 休息是为了走更长远的路
Periods of rest are required to operate at peak efficiency.
而且 我是个爱找乐子的人
Besides, I'm a fun guy.
- 那我们什么时候出发 - 就是现在
- When do we leave? - Right now.
在你改变心意之前
Before you change your mind.
嘿 我想要一支冰棒
Oh, man, I wanted one of those freezer pops.
谢啦 野兽小子
Thanks, Beast Boy!
我通常不太吃莱姆口味 但这个还不错
I usually hate the lime ones. This one's way better.
是因为有我的口水吧
That's because it has my spit on it.
我现在觉得肚子不太舒服
Whoa. Now I am feeling the sickness of the stomach.
在蝙蝠冰箱上的是一些紧急电话的清单
Here on the Bat-refrigerator is a list of emergency numbers,
包含警察局局长戈登的电话
including Commissioner Gordon's cell.
如果你找不到我 打给他 任何时间都可以
If you can't reach me, call him day or night.
没问题 你就尽管去享受假期吧
No problem, worrywart. Just try and have a good time.
还有 八点后罗宾就不准打电动
Also, no video games for Robin after 8:30.
不然他在睡觉前 会太兴奋
It gets him all wound up before his bedtime.
什么 办派对是我的主意耶 我也要去啊
What? This whole party was my idea! I'm totally coming, too!
在学期中吗 我不准
On a school night? I don't think so.
你不是想增加战斗能力 还有属于自己的房子
Positive reinforcement? Self-esteem building?
我们之前讨论过了
We talked about this.
罗宾 我觉得蝙蝠侠的意思是说
Robin, I think what Batman is saying is
他无法将哥谭市交给他不信任的人
that he can't trust Gotham City to an outsider.
你很熟悉这里 可以帮助超人
You know this town and need to look out for Superman.
蝙蝠侠 你说是吧
Isn't that right, Batman?
是的
Sure.
没问题 蝙蝠侠 我懂你的意思了
Okay, Batman. Gotcha.
别让他惹上任何麻烦
Keep the Big Blue Boy Scout out of trouble.
没问题 嘿 你还在这啊
Indeed. Hey, are you still here?
罗宾和我已经要去执行任务了 对吧 伙伴
Because Robin and I really need to get on with our duties. Right, pally?
是的 超人
Right, Superman!
再见啦 祝你旅途愉快
So long! Farewell! Happy travels!
超人 你准备好要见哥谭市了吗
Ready to patrol the city, Superman?
我可以带你看看哥谭市最危险的地方
I can show you where all the most dangerous criminals like to lurk.
不了 罗宾 我想你今天的任务就是把你的功课写完
No, Robin, I'm afraid your first duty tonight is to complete your homework!
- 但是… - 不不不
- But... - Uh-uh-uh.
蛋是拿来吃的 不是说的
Butts are for sittin'. Not for sassin'.
这是我妈以前常说的话 我以前都听不懂
'Least that's what my ma used to say. Never understood it.
快去吧 小伙子
Let's go, youngster.
你不如把我抓去关牢房里
You might as well send me to jail.
阿卡姆疯人院
我们帮你把你房间整理好了 哈莉
We kept your old cell warm for ya, Harley.
嘿 像你这么爱开玩笑的女生
Hey, for a girl who likes to play jokes,
为什么笑到最后的都是蝙蝠侠啊
why is it that Batman always gets the last laugh?
瞧你说得真好
Ha! See what you did there. Good one.
每个人都很会说笑话啊
Ha. Everyone's a comedian.
嘿 小丑先生 我回来了
Hey, Mr. J! I'm home!
那是什么啊
What's this?
看来蝙蝠侠要离开了啊
Looks like the Bats are leaving the belfry!
嗯 蝙蝠侠一离开 小丑来捣蛋
Well, while the Bats are away, the Joker will play!
这就不太好笑了
That's really not very funny.
真的不太好笑 只是把老鼠和猫的俚语改一改
No, it's not even a clever twist on the popular idiom involving cats and mice.
是啊
Agreed.
人类就是意见很多
Everyone's a critic.
亲爱的小汤匙 只剩你和我了 我把你偷偷带出厨房
It's you and me now, Spoony. I liberated you from the kitchen.
机会是需要等待的 你愿意帮我吗
Time to return the favor. Can you do it?
当然啦
Sure thing, loser!
汤匙汤匙 你真是太棒了
Oh, Spoony, you're the greatest.
我们要去度假啦 我们要去度假啦
We're going on vacation! We're going on vacation!
我们要去度假啦
We're on vacation!
承认吧 这是有史以来最棒的主意
Admit it, this was the best idea ever!
是啊 真是让人耳目一新
Yes, and it's been quite refreshing.
该回哥谭市了吧
Time to head back to Gotham.
放轻松 蝙蝠侠 你会玩得很开心的
Oh, relax, Batman, you're going to have a great time.
你一定猜不到我们安排了什么行程
You'll never guess what we've got lined up for you.
依照你多余的感性
Based on your excessive sentimentality,
我确信你会帮我安排一趟回忆之旅
I theorize that you are taking me on a trip down memory lane,
追溯过往的脚步去找以前的师父们
retracing my formative steps with the various mentors
曾经帮助我成为蝙蝠侠的师父们
who helped me to become the Batman.
不 你错了 我们要带你去的是一趟回忆之旅
Ha! Wrong! We're taking you on a trip down memory lane!
追溯过往的脚步去找以前的师…
Retracing your formative steps with the various mentors who...
别太过要求自己了 小男孩
Don't be too hard on yourself, former Boy Wonder.
在这世界上最有可能的目的地就是
The only possible destination in this part of the world
在地图上未标示的小岛屿
is this tiny uncharted atoll,
我之前师父的家 敬爱的曼提斯女士
the home of my old instructor, the venerable Madame Mantis.
我们已经和曼提斯女士通信好几个礼拜了
We've been exchanging emails with Madame Mantis for weeks now.
她似乎是位慈祥和蔼的女士 而你是她最爱的学生
She seems like such a sweet old lady. You're her all-time favorite student.
原来你也想见见她
I just knew you'd want to see her.
慈祥和蔼的女士 她能教你什么啊
"Sweet old lady"? What did she teach you, Bats?
餐桌礼仪和仪态吗
Table manners and etiquette?
我想你的确需要好好教教礼仪 小伙子
I think you could do with a lesson in manners, sonny.
嘿 你是从哪冒出来的 我都没听到…
Hey! Where'd you come from? I didn't hear you...
这里不对
Pointing?
叔叔 叔叔
Uncle! Uncle!
我可是一直都能听到你的声音啊 乳臭未干的小鬼
I couldn't help but hear you clomping around, bird boy.
曼提斯女士
Madame Mantis.
请您原谅我这个不成熟又无礼的学徒
Please forgive the brash rudeness of my former apprentice.
他的年纪尚轻才如此莽撞
His youth leads him to foolishness.
他可没有你以前那么无礼喔 我的徒弟
He is no more brash or foolhardy than you were, my former student.
我很开心你能回来 小蝙蝠
I welcome you back with gladness in my heart, Batface.
小蝙蝠
"Batface"?
曼提斯女士 我也很开心…
Madame Mantis, it is so good to...
鞠躬时眼神再低些
You lowered your eyes during your bow.
你在哥谭市的安逸生活让你更软弱了
Your easy life in Gotham City has made you soft!
请原谅我 老师
Forgive me, sensei.
请原谅我
"Forgive me"?
曼提斯女士 这位是蝙蝠女
Madame Mantis, this is Batgirl.
嗨 我们之前有通过信
Hi, we met online.
然后你已经打… 见过夜翼了
And you've already hit... Uh, met Nightwing.
请原谅我展示对年轻人好客的艺术
Allow me to demonstrate to these young ones the art of hospitality.
在长途的旅程之后要不要来点醒脑茶呢
May I offer you some refreshing tea after your long journey?
不不不 不用客气
No, no, no. We're fine.
我们在飞机上有喝的 真的…
We had some on the plane. Really...
听起来真是不错啊 曼提斯女士
Why that sounds just lovely, Madame Mantis.
茶 听起来不错啊 我是该喝点热热的…茶
Tea? Now that's more like it. I would love some nice, hot... Tea!
拜托 曼提斯女士
Please, Madame Mantis!
后来想想 我好像比较喜欢喝咖啡
On second thought, I'm more of a coffee person.
你要一块还是两块糖
You want one lump or two?
你们的破绽太多了
You must be the space between the teacups.
曼提斯女士不按常理出牌的教学方式
Madame Mantis' unconventional teaching methods
总是能够训练出适应各种攻击的能力
instill absolute situational awareness at all times.
你现在才说
You're telling me?
我以为你是最严格的老师了
And I thought you were a tough teacher.
我尽力了
I did my best,
但是我的训练在这里根本不算什么
but my training doesn't hold a candle to the instruction I received here.
你还沉迷在过去啊 小蝙蝠
You wallow in nostalgia, Batface.
沉迷在过去是傻子才会做的事
Nostalgia is the path a fool walks to a pity party.
只有傻子才会让自己困在没有门的笼子里
And a pity party is nothing but a stuffed bird in a cage with no door.
不是吗
Or is it?
是的 我懂了
Yes. I see...
等等 你到底想表达什么 曼提斯女士
Wait, what? What are you trying to teach me, Madame Mantis?
我要说的是
Only this,
当你在听取智慧之语时 能够接得下突如其来的攻击吗
a man who does not expect a surprise attack in the middle of hearing wisdom
就像虫一样…
is like a worm who...
现在你们知道我为什么从来不上课了吧
And you wonder why I never come to class reunions.
来吧 我亲爱的学生 就像以前一样
Come now, student. It will be just like old times.
这就是我担心的
That's what I'm afraid of.
蝙蝠侠 上啊
Go get her, Batman!
不准笑
No giggling.
你还保有你从这里学到的技能
You have kept much of the skill you learned here,
但是你还是缺少打败我的本事
but you still lack the ability to defeat me.
你的期末考就是 不要有怜悯之心
For your final test, you must attack without mercy!
不可能
Never!
不是你打败我 就是我打败你
Either you destroy me or I destroy you!
曼提斯女士 请停止这场打斗
Madame Mantis, stop this madness!
停止这场打斗的唯一方法就是使用禁忌的攻击
The only way to stop anything is for you to use the forbidden move!
禁忌的攻击
"Forbidden move"?
夜翼 那是什么啊 什么是禁忌的攻击
Nightwing, what is that? What's the "forbidden move"?
我也不确定
I'm not completely sure,
但是我想就是一种攻击 不知道为什么
but I think it's some kind of move that, for reasons unknown,
是完全被禁止使用的
has been completely forbidden.
谢谢你喔
Thanks.
小蝙蝠 这是唯一能够救你的方式
It is the only way to save yourself, Batface.
不 不要插手 这是我的战斗
No, stay back. This is my fight.
而且就快结束了
And it's about to end.
小蝙蝠终于要开始战斗了
Ooh! Batface is finally ready to fight!
动手啊 杀了我 这样你的训练就完成了
Do it! Finish me and your training will be complete.
蝙蝠侠 不可以
Batman, you can't!
不
No!
曼提斯女士其实是个男的
Madame Mantis is really a man?
而且非常非常的丑
A very, very, very, ugly man.
男人 也不是喔
"Man"? Hardly!
我只是刚好长得这么丑 如果你记得我我会很感谢
It just so happens that I am a Trogowog, and I'll thank you not to forget it.
老实说 从笨拙的攻击方式 我就知道是你了
Obviously, I immediately knew from your clumsy attack
你根本不可能是曼提斯女士
that you couldn't be the real Madame Mantis.
但我一直在假装不知情才能知道你到底想干嘛
But I played along to find out what you were up to.
那你到底是谁
But who are you?
你为什么要假扮蝙蝠侠的师父
And why did you impersonate Batman's old master?
我才不会告诉你
I shan't tell you.
我是装扮成老女人的丑丑格
I am an enigma wrapped in a riddle wrapped in a stifling old woman costume.
那蝙蝠侠 以你的推测 你能知道些什么
What do your powers of deduction tell you, Batman?
我只知道他为一个训练有素且装备齐全的佣兵集团效力
I know only that he's working for a highly-trained and well-equipped mercenary.
你怎么可能知道这件事
How can you possibly know that?
从一个刚刚跑到我们脚边的烟雾弹就知道了
From the hi-tech smoke bomb that just landed at our feet.
你们看
Look!
说跟我说的一样 是丧钟
Just as I suspected. Deathstroke.
丧钟怎么会在这里
Deathstroke? Here?
那不是佣兵吗
Isn't he some kind of mercenary?
是啊 他是世界上唯一最致命的佣兵
Uh, yeah. He's only the most deadly mercenary in the world.
伪装的杀手 致命的佣兵
Disguised killers. Deadly mercenaries.
我从来没有这么想念过哥谭市的和平和宁静
I never thought I'd be homesick for the peace and quiet of Gotham City.
不能放过他们
We mustn't lose them.
他们是找到曼提斯女士的唯一希望
They're our only hope of finding the real Madame Mantis.
话少讲 赶快追吧
Less talk. More Bat-pursuit.
我想在他来之前我还有时间喝杯咖啡
I guess I have time to brew a fresh pot of coffee before he gets here.
我的天啊 蝙蝠侠 你比以前还要快…
My goodness, Batman, that was faster than...
你一定就是戈登局长 我是超人
You must be Commissioner Gordon. I'm Superman.
我知道你是谁
Yes, I know who you are.
我会做好黑暗骑士的工作 在他去度假的时候
I'm filling in for the Dark Knight while he's away on vacation.
度假
Vacation?
你知道的 蝙蝠侠他说了不少你的好话
You know, Batman cannot say enough good things about you.
事实上 他都是用闲聊的方式 嗯 蝙蝠侠嘛
He's practically chatty about it! Well, for Batman, anyway.
我们说的是同一个人吗
Are we talking about the same guy?
发生了什么事吗 局长
What seems to be the problem, Commissioner?
- 罗宾 你不是应该… - 功课写完啦
- Robin? I thought you were... - Homework done!
是时候该打击犯罪了
Time to fight some crime.
是小丑
It's the Joker.
那个疯子 他又一次从阿卡姆疯人院逃跑了
That madcap madman has escaped from Arkham Asylum. Again!
小丑 事情大条了
The Joker! That's about as serious as it can get.
我们最好赶快联络蝙蝠侠 告诉他…
We'd better contact Batman and inform him of...
什么 要破坏他的假期吗 不可能
What? And ruin his vacation? Nonsense!
这个小丑就是装扮成小丑的样子嘛
The Joker's the guy in the clown makeup, right?
他看起来是小丑 但是他一点都不好笑
He may look like a clown, but he's no joke.
蝙蝠侠有专门制伏小丑的方法
Batman has a specific Joker protocol to follow.
首先 要先集中…
First we round up his known associate...
我们没有要集中什么好吗 小伙子
We are not rounding up anything, Boy Wonder.
哈啰 明天还要上课
Hello? It's a school night.
成长中的孩子需要八小时的充足睡眠
A growing boy needs eight hours of sleep.
我觉得我能自己解决这个没超能力的小丑 谢谢你喔
I think I can handle this non-powered clown all by myself, thank you.
嗯 如果蝙蝠侠不在的话
Well, if Batman must be out of town,
是应该要有一个有相当能力的超级英雄 就像…
it's good to know he left Gotham in the capable hands of a hero like...
- 你还在啊 - 不然我要去哪
- You're still here. - Why wouldn't I be?
我不知道啊 我以为你会不见
I don't know, I thought you'd be gone.
你还在讲话耶 那不是很没礼貌吗
You were still talking. That'd be incredibly rude.
而且 如果你要讲的是很重要的事呢
Besides, what if you said something important?
嗯 我一直都尽量不要把重要的事放到最后才讲
Well, I try not to save any important information till the end.
没有啦 快去抓小丑吧 祝你好运
Never mind. Just go get the Joker. And good luck!
局长 我不需要好运就可以搞定 超人已经接手了
No need for luck, Commissioner. Superman is on the case!
我会把小丑抓回阿卡姆 然后把罗宾赶上床睡觉
I'll have the Joker back in Arkham and Robin off to bed in no time.
走吧 小伙子
Come, Boy Wonder.
原来 对话正常结束 就是像这样子
So, that's what it's like to finish a conversation.
真不错
Not bad.
丧钟的足迹只到这了 就跟我担心的一样
Deathstroke's tracks lead here. Just as I feared.
这该死的是什么地方啊
Holy hole in the wall!
你都是这样讲话的吗
You actually say things like that.
我也不是每次都会说该死啦
I do not say "Holy" all the time.
我以前还是罗宾的时候 就会像那样说话
I said it a couple times back when I was Robin and it became a "thing."
我从来不会这样 但是 我是说 你看看这个
I really never do it. But, come on, I mean, look at this.
我们需要蝙蝠船 就可以继续追上丧钟
We'll need the Bat Hover Boat to follow Deathstroke
还有他的丑丑格们 不管他们要去哪里
and his Trogowog accomplice where they're going.
我们要去哪里弄一艘船 而且是在这种鬼地方
Where are we going to get a hovercraft in the middle of, uh, nowhere?
这东西突然出现在这里 真是一点都不惊讶啊
This sort of thing really shouldn't come as a surprise to you by now.
仔细听好了
Listen carefully.
我们要去的地方 将会测试你内心的极限
Where we're about to go will test the limits of your mind.
我们接下来要经历的 将会测试你灵魂是否坚毅
What we're about to experience will test the fortitude of your very soul.
你不仅会看到这个墙后面
You will not simply gaze upon the secrets and mysteries
掩盖的秘密和谎言
that lie beyond these walls.
他们一样也会盯着你
They will gaze into you.
一旦进去就无法回头
There's no dishonor in backing out...
- 我要参加 - 走吧
- I'm in! - Let's do this!
小丑小丑小丑
Joker, Joker, Joker.
小丑在哪里
Where is the Joker?
这是超人的手机 我是超人 需要帮忙吗
Superman's cell phone. Superman speaking, how can I help you?
- 我是罗宾 - 嗨 罗宾
- It's Robin. - Hi, Robin.
等等 你不是该上床睡觉了吗
Wait. Isn't it your bedtime?
正准备 你找到小丑了没
Working on it. Have you found the Joker yet?
这没有想象中简单 哥谭市又黑又雾蒙蒙
It's not easy. It's so dark and gritty here in Gotham.
大城市不是应该白净明亮吗
Metropolis is all clean and white.
这样罪犯才好抓啊
It's easier to pick out the criminals.
找到了 他在那里 我会尽快把他抓起来的
Bingo! There he is. I'll have him locked up in no time.
超人 小心点
Be careful, Superman.
小丑可是蝙蝠侠遇到过的最狡猾奸诈的敌人
The Joker is one of Batman's trickiest foes.
是啊 我知道没超能力的坏蛋对没超能力的英雄来说是个挑战
Yes, I'm sure a non-powered foe can be a challenge for a non-powered hero.
我该走了 要抓坏人了
Gotta go, bad guy to catch.
小汤匙 你说是不是很棒
Oh, Spoony, isn't it wonderful?
蝙蝠侠一不在 哥谭市就任我玩了
With Batsy gone, all of Gotham is our own funhouse.
小丑 犯罪不是游戏
There's nothing fun about crime, Joker.
你看 小汤匙
Look, Spoony.
小蝙蝠跑去度假 还请小超人来看家啊
Batsy decided to leave Little Boy Blue to watch the house while he's away.
这真是太好玩了
This is gonna be fun.
嗯 我想好玩的应该是你和你的汤匙
Uh, yes, well, the only fun you and your, uh, spoon will be having
会乖乖回到阿卡姆的房间
is back in your cell at Arkham.
不 你不可能把我们带回去
No, you'll never take us back there.
小汤匙不会答应回去
Spoony will never allow it.
放弃吧 小丑 我有超能力
Give up now, Joker. I have superpowers,
而你只有…
and all you have is a...
- 一只汤匙 - 超能力 例如说呢
- A spoon. - Superpowers? Like what?
你可以把树变成钱吗
Can you grow money from trees?
嗯 不行
Well, no.
你可以把狗隐形吗
Can you make dogs invisible?
小汤匙 那根本不是超能力
Spoony, that's not even a real superpower.
可以展示一下给小汤匙看吗
Perhaps a demonstration for Spoony?
嗯 我可以很准确地从眼睛射出镭射光
Well, I can shoot super-hot beams from my eyes with super-accuracy.
真的吗 证明给我看啊
Oh, really? Prove it, you big goof.
阿卡姆疯人院
小汤匙 做得好
Oh, well done, Spoony.
谢啦 超级小丑
Thanks, Super-sucker.
蝙蝠侠看到一定会不开心
Batman will not be happy about this.
好了小丑 也许你能戏弄我一次 或两次
All right, Joker, you may have tricked me once or twice.
我开始了解蝙蝠侠为什么需要放假了
I'm starting to see why the Bat bunch wanted that vacation.
你对于你假期还满意吗
How do you like your vacation so far?
漂亮的环境 充满冒险
Beautiful surroundings, a touch of adventure.
- 有瀑布 - 瀑布
- Waterfall! - Waterfall?
- 喔 拜托 - 好吧 这是个无底洞
- Come on. - Okay, this thing is bottomless.
无底洞其实不可能存在
A bottomless pit is a spatial impossibility.
这只不过是很深很深的洞
This is just a very, very, very deep hole.
你知道吗 你的秘密对我来说已经够多了
You know, your secrets have gazed into me, enough already.
你什么时候才要告诉我们这到底是怎么一回事
When are you going to tell us what's really going on here?
我还不知道这件事什么时候会结束
I've not yet deduced the end of this mystery.
我只知道很久以前开始的
But the beginning of it began long ago,
当我和丧钟还是好朋友的时候
when Deathstroke and I were best friends.
事情开始于我们都还是曼提斯女士道场里的学生
It all started when I had just become a student at Madame Mantis' dojo.
我还清楚地记得
I remember it so clearly.
我们的第一课就是手工艺术
Our very first class together was Arts and Crafts.
时间到了 小鬼们 把你们艺术品给我看
Time's up, miserable rookies. Show me your art now.
不错啊 有钱的小鬼
Not bad, rich kid.
你真是纸类艺术界的米开朗基罗
You are a regular Michelangelo in papier-mâché.
从现在开始 我就叫你小蝙蝠
From now on, I'll call you Batface.
给我看你的吧 丧气鬼
Show me yours, sourpuss.
太可怕了
Ah! Scary.
我还没完成啊 我才画好一半而已
I'm not finished, I only painted half of it.
相信我 完成也好不到哪里去
Believe me, it won't help.
对我来说 这作品已死
You'll be the death of me, boy.
真是太可怕了 简直差点把我吓死
That's so terrifying, it almost gave me a stroke.
从现在开始 我要叫你钟丧
From now on, I'll call you Strokedeath.
听起来很奇怪耶 叫丧钟好吗
Oh. That sounds weird. How about Deathstroke?
钟丧
Strokedeath!
曼提斯女士对我的特殊训练
Madame Mantis' preferential treatment of me
是我和史莱德关系破裂的最后关键
eventually set the stage for my relationship with Slade.
小蝙蝠 做得好
Very good, Batface.
你已经掌握了我教给你的所有技能
You have mastered all the techniques I have given you.
只剩下最后一个
There is but one skill left...
那就是禁忌的攻击
The forbidden move.
我很乐意学习曼提斯女士所有的课程
I would be honored to learn whatever Madame Mantis deems fit.
不 我来得比较久 我的年级比较高
No, I have been here longer. I am the senior student.
你应该先教我才对
You have to teach me the technique first.
我只教准备好的人
I teach what I teach to those ready to be taught.
而你还没准备好 钟丧
And you are not ready, Strokedeath.
我是丧钟 而且我已经准备好了
It's Deathstroke and I'm ready for anything.
我是史莱德·威尔森
I am Slade Wilson.
我做什么都是最棒的
I am the best at everything I do,
而你却要把技能都教给这个笨蛋
and you waste your senile talents on this fool?
我也不需要你的什么愚蠢禁忌攻击
I don't need you or your stupid forbidden move.
我会成世界上最厉害的打手
I'll become the greatest fighter the world has ever known,
而我会自己完成
and I'll do it on my own.
我好多年没有看到史莱德
I didn't see Slade again for years.
当我再次见到他 他已经成为丧钟
The next time I saw him, he had become Deathstroke,
世界上最致命的佣兵
the world's most deadly mercenary.
- 好的 所以你也有年轻的时候 - 那个丑丑的家伙呢
- Okay, wow, you were a kid once? - What about that Trogowog dude?
以后再说
To be continued.
欢迎来到丑恶基地
Welcome to the land of the Trogowogs.
由曼提斯女士守护
A secret world protected by Madame Mantis
是人类从未到过的地方
and hidden from the corruptive influence of mankind.
欢迎光临 蝙蝠侠
Welcome, Batman.
别动 你就在那里等着被我抓
Don't move, I've got you right where I want you.
- 是谁要被抓 - 是我会抓住你
- Who's got who? - I've got you.
我最爱惊喜派对了 你说是吗
Oh, how I love a surprise party. Wouldn't you agree?
没有错 他们都吓了一跳
Indubitably, they were wonderfully surprised.
丧钟主人 做得好
Good show, Master Deathstroke.
蝙蝠侠 蝙蝠女还有夜翼
Batman, Batgirl and Nightwing...
真开心看到你…
So nice of you to...
如果你要说真开心看到你掉进来
If you say, "Nice of you to drop in,"
你的确是个超级坏蛋
you immediately lose all credibility as a supervillain.
- 我没有要那样说 - 那你要说什么
- That's not what I was going to say. - Oh, what were you going to say?
嗯 我现在不想讲了
Well, I don't want to tell you now.
而至于你 小蝙蝠
And as for you, Batface,
如果你还想要你的师父多活五秒
if you want your junior helpers to survive the next five seconds,
你知道该怎么做吧
you know what to do.
如果你以为这样就能让黑暗骑士投降
If you think the mighty Dark Knight is about to surrender,
你就大错特错了
you've got another...
我收回刚刚说的
I stand corrected.
来吧 好吃的披萨
Come to me, my yummy piece of pepperoni.
嗨 你好 我是钢骨
Hey, there... Uh, Cyborg.
嗨 超人
Wow, Superman, hi.
我绝对没有在监控台前吃披萨
I definitely wasn't eating pizza at the Hall of Justice very special table.
很好 很好 太好了
Ah. Good, good. Fantastic.
超人 一切都…
Superman, is anything...
- 还好吗 - 什么
- Wrong? - What?
很好 很好 一切都很好
No, no, everything's great.
我只是在想 也许你有空出来聚聚
I just thought maybe you might want to uh, hang out a little.
你知道嘛 就是你们常说的
You know, like you kids say.
还有啊 也许你可以来伸个援手
You know what? Maybe a little help around here
- 我是非常地欢迎你喔 - 嘿 神奇女侠在这儿
- wouldn't be completely unwelcome. - Hey, Wonder Woman's here.
- 你要问问她吗 - 不 不 不
- You want to ask her? - No! No, no, no.
不需要打扰她 我们自己处理就好
No need to bother her, we got this.
也不需要去找正义联盟的其他人
No real reason to mention it to anyone in the League, ever.
好的 我懂了 就你和我 我很乐意帮忙打击犯罪
Oh. Okay. Whatever. Happy to help. Just you and me, taking on crime.
- 我们一定合作无间 - 没有错
- We'll be a great team. - Absolutely.
就像蝙蝠侠和罗宾 好啦 等会见
Just like Batman and Robin. Fine, see you soon.
马上见 要快点喔
Very soon. Please hurry.
"就像蝙蝠侠和罗宾"
"Just like Batman and Robin."
别弄了 你们这群像猴子的东西
Quit it, you little cave-monkey-thing.
我们像猴子
Cave-monkey-thing?
- 不像啊 - 先生 我们是丑丑格
- Well, I never. - Dear sir, we are Trogowogs.
我们是很古老的物种 在你们出现前就居住在地球上了
An ancient species that walked the Earth long before you surface dwellers arrived.
而你无礼的言辞已经伤害到了我们
And your brash words have vexed our refined sensibilities.
丧钟 你对我们的师父到底做了什么
What have you done with our sensei, Deathstroke?
曼提斯人还好好的
The old Mantis is fine, Batman.
就目前来就
For now.
曼提斯女士守护丑丑格 就像牡蛎保护珍珠一样
Madame Mantis guarded the secret of the Trogowogs like a pearl inside an oyster,
既安全又隐密 是在深山里且无法轻易抵达
inside a safe, inside a vault, inside a mountain with no door.
但是你却进来了
But somehow you found a way in.
蝙蝠侠 一开始进来的不是我
Not me, Batman.
这些秘密快把你搞疯了是吗
The mystery is just killing you isn't it?
我真爱看你这样
I'm enjoying that.
我可不是那种会交代细节又爱碎碎念的坏蛋
But I'm not the villain who will be monologuing the plot details.
你很快就会见到他了
You'll meet him soon enough.
碎碎念 这形容词是不是不太好
"Monologuing"? That's not a proper word, is it?
我不会说这个词
Well, I should say not.
他们地面上的人都很喜欢讲粗话
Surface dwellers seem to have a mania for slang.
班恩
Bane.
我觉得你应该称呼我为班恩大帝
I think you mean "Lord Bane," Batman.
丧钟和班恩 他们联手了
Deathstroke and Bane? Working together?
可能只是一起买面具吧
Maybe they met while mask shopping.
欢迎来到我的地下王国
Welcome to my underground nation.
这是新的班恩多尼亚王国
The newly named Bane-donia.
班恩蓝尼亚
Bane-landia?
那班恩席尼维亚
Bane-sylvania.
- 班恩达尼史坦 - 你再想想吧
- Bane-danistan? - Needs work.
班恩 不管你要叫它什么 你占据丑丑格的计划
Whatever you call it, Bane, your totalitarian occupation of these Trogowogs
都注定会失败
is destined to fail.
尽管你处心积虑得到他们控制心灵的水晶
Despite your fiendish use of their mind-influencing crystal,
也就是心智石
the Psyche Stone.
你看吧 我就跟你说过了
You see? I told you.
那个老曼提斯把所有秘密都跟他讲了
The old Mantis shared all of her secrets with him.
嗯 真希望有人能把事情讲清楚 因为我都搞不清楚
Well, I wish would share some secrets with us because I got nothing.
我不知道现在是什么状况
I got no idea what's going on here.
这就是碎碎念吗
And cue monologue.
- 我最喜欢听故事了 - 要开始了
- Ooh! I do so love a good story. - Ssh! It's about to begin.
- 嗯 你看看 - 班恩一定是用那颗心智石
- Well, you see... - Bane must be using that Psyche Stone
控制了丑丑格的心智 来建立他的军队
to mentally transform the Trogowogs into assassins infused with his fury
以及丧钟的武术技能
and Deathstroke's martial arts skills.
- 但是这只是第一步 - 当然
- Ah. But that's only part... - Ooh. Of course.
他要建立一个军队来对抗整个世界
He's creating an army to conquer the world, no doubt.
为了使他的军队坚不可摧 他要他们学习禁忌的攻击
And in order to make his army undefeatable he needs them to learn the forbidden move.
- 但是… - 所以他们绑架了曼提斯女士
- But... - So they kidnapped Madame Mantis
试图透过心智石来让曼提斯女士教授禁忌的攻击
and tried to extract the forbidden move from her mind using the Psyche Stone.
- 对 然后呢 - 但是他们失败了
- Yes, and... - But they failed
因为曼提斯女士的心太过坚定
because her will is too strong.
所以他们把目标转向我 要控制我的心灵
So they lured me here to try to pry the secret from my mind.
- 真是太厉害了 - 很厉害的推理
- Brilliant. - Well played.
你知道吗 大侦探 你这样会剥夺坏蛋的乐趣
You know, detectives, you take the fun out of being a villain sometimes.
有时候啦
But only sometimes.
- 祝你有美好的一天 - 你也是
- Good day to you. - And you.
- 我不会说的 - 你不用说啊
- I'll never talk. - You won't have to.
再过一段时间 心智石就会直接
It's only a matter of time before the Psyche Stone
呈现我们想要知道的东西
rips the information we want directly from your mind.
快啊 蝙蝠侠 快告诉我们吧
Come now, Batman. Share and share alike.
- 你等着收尸吧 - 很快就会了
- Over my dead body. - That can be arranged.
心智石的能力是相当致命的
The Psyche Stone energy is deadly,
而且你也已经承受好一阵子了
and you've been bathing in it for quite some time.
对 快告诉我们吧 快给我们看我们渴求的东西
Yes, show us. Show us what we want to know.
快告诉我们什么是禁忌的攻击
Show us the forbidden move.
是电影放映的形式耶
Oh, it's a motion picture story.
今天真是个刺激的一天
Mmm. This is such an exciting day.
看仔细了 小蝙蝠
Watch carefully, Batface.
我不是每天都会展示禁忌的攻击
I don't go around showing the forbidden move every day.
- 这会是考试的一部份吗 - 是的 在你的一生中都是
- Is this going to be on the test? - Yes, the test of life!
先好好观察 我再解说
Observe and marvel at the forbidden move.
要开始了
Oh! Here it comes.
真是太厉害了
Amazing.
师父 但是我告诉过你 我发过誓不杀人
But I told you, Master, I've vowed never to take a life.
这个攻击并不会致死
This move does not kill.
但是后果会更严重
It is worse.
它会使身体变成碎片
It splits the body into pieces,
但是却依然活着
but life remains.
- 太酷了 - 太酷了
- Awesome! - Awesome!
- 太可怕了 - 就是
- That's horrible. - Duh!
我知道 所以它才被称之为禁忌的攻击
I know, that's why it's called the forbidden move.
- 那为什么要教我这个 - 我是老师 我来决定要教什么
- Then why show me it at all? - Hey, who's the master here?
现在呢 很简单 你只要把你的手弄成C的形状
Now, it's very simple, you just form your hand into a C-shape
然后…
and...
不
No!
才刚进入故事最精彩的部份
Oh, I say, it was only just arriving at the good part.
突然就这样结束了
Mmm, how very anticlimactic.
把他移回心智光束下 我们一定要知道那个秘密
Get back in that beam. We must have that secret.
不 他只剩一口气了
No, he's barely surviving now.
如果光束在我们知道秘密前杀死了他 就前功尽弃了
If the beam destroys him before we have our prize, it is lost to us forever.
拜托 丧钟 你的热情和好客的态度呢
Come now, Deathstroke, where is your spirit of hospitality?
把他放到客房里去
Put him in the Presidential Suite.
该死的一团糟 哥谭市到处都是罪犯
Holy garbage truck, Gotham City is filthy with criminals.
该死的什么 你怎么这样讲话
Holy what? Why are you talking like that?
等等 你以前不穿斗篷的不是吗 钢骨
Wait, you don't usually wear a cape, do you, Cyborg?
是啊
Uh. Yes.
Yes, I do.
你可以叫我神奇小子吗
And would you please call me Boy Wonder?
X光扫射显示
X-ray vision reveals...
我想我们找到的女性罪犯叫做毒藤女
I believe we've found the lady criminal called Poison Ivy.
真是该死的藤蔓 蝙蝠… 我是说超人
Holy horticulture, Bat... I mean Superman.
- 那现在该怎么办 - 跟我来
- What do we do now? - Follow my lead.
在你的脸变绿之前 我们得把这植物送回花盆里
We'll have this plant back in her pot before you can say "evergreen."
不错喔
Not bad.
抱歉 女士 我很遗憾地告诉你 你逍遥的日子要结束了
I'm sorry, ma'am, but I'm afraid your thieving days are over.
你们是不会对女士动手的 对吧 男士们
You wouldn't hit a lady, would you, boys?
为什么要动手 当然不会
Why, no. Of course not.
- 我是说… - 很好
- But I mean... - Good.
这比我想象中的还困难
This may be more difficult than I thought.
- 要叫神奇女侠了吗 - 好吧 呼叫神奇女侠
- Wonder Woman? - Okay. Call Wonder Woman.
这些地底下的光 是植物自发性的光芒
With the light of the underworld coming from bioluminescent plants
而奇怪的发光石头 居然可以一直发光
and strange phosphorescent stones, it's a land of perpetual day,
不太可能争取时间
impossible to keep time, yet...
但我们还是要试试
We must try.
- 我们在这里已经快一小时了 - 是的 没错
- We've been here for about an hour. - That sounds about right.
那里有人吗
Is someone there?
是恐怖的人类 退后
Monstrous humans, stay back!
曼提斯女士
Madame Mantis.
- 她一定是真的曼提斯女士 - 她是真的 但是很虚弱
- It must be the real one. - She's quite real and quite weak.
我的拐杖
My cane.
在这里
Here it is.
你还好吗
Are you all right? Ow!
我当然不好啦 你这个笨蛋
Of course I'm not all right, dumbo.
我被那石头折腾了两个礼拜
I've been tortured by a magic rock for two weeks.
但是我没有被打败
But I didn't break.
我不知道她是怎么撑过来的 曼提斯非常强大
I don't know how she endured it. Mantis is so very strong.
而我呢 非常没用
I, on the other hand, am so very weak.
孩子 你没有那么糟
Oh, you're not so bad, kid.
你把我照顾得很好啊
You take good care of Madame Mantis.
这是格格王子 这地方的领导者
This is Prince Grungle, rightful ruler of this place.
他们来了 快点 我们要躲起来
They're coming. Quickly, we must cower.
蝙蝠侠
Batman!
离她远一点 你这个畜牲
Stay away from her, you brute.
这位是王子还是什么
Some prince you turned out to be.
都是一群没用的水母
Yes, all the backbone of a jellyfish.
能够遇到班恩我们真是太幸运了
Lucky for us, Bane showed up when he did.
我永远不会说出
Never
禁忌的攻击
tell forbidden move.
小蝙蝠 我很抱歉 但是你一定会说出来的
Oh, I'm sorry, but you will, Batface.
曼提斯女士
Madame Mantis.
他们的心智石力量太大
That stone of theirs is strong.
即使是我也快承受不住
Almost too strong, even for me.
都是我的错
Oh, this is all my fault.
当班恩来这里的时候 因为我能力太弱而无法阻止
When Bane arrived here, I was too weak to stop him.
- 而且还胆小 - 夜翼
- Also a little bit chicken. - Nightwing.
格格王子很明显是个好人
Prince Grungle is clearly one of the good guys.
你可以尊重他一下吗
A little respect?
不用 不用 他说的是对的
No, no, he's quite right.
我根本就不是什么王子
I am no real prince.
一个合格的王子应该是无畏的 在战争时挺身而出
A proper prince would've been brave, put up a fight.
但是我不知道该怎么做
But I didn't know how.
丑丑格是个爱好和平的民族
We Trogowogs have always been a peaceful people.
我们会用神秘石来散播友情和爱情
We used the sacred stone to spread friendship and love.
一直到班恩来后
Until Bane arrived.
他听到了关于我们拥有巨大财富的谣言
He had heard whispers of our existence, rumors of our great wealth.
经过长久的搜寻 终于找到了我们
Finally, after a long search, he found us
他使用了心智石让族人们学会仇恨
and used the Psych Stone to teach our people to hate.
班恩杀死我爸爸 也就是我们国王 而我也眼睁睁的看着
He destroyed my father, the king, while I watched,
感受那样的恐惧
frozen in fear.
现在的丑丑格十分残忍 而且被凶恶的国王统治着
Now the Trogowogs are a violent mob and follow a king of hate.
格格王子 别太苛求你的人民了
Don't be too hard on your people, Grungle.
班恩的确是个很可怕的人
Bane is pretty scary.
而且每个人都有害怕的时候
And everyone is afraid sometimes.
所谓勇敢是你诚实面对你的恐惧
Bravery is just fighting for what you know is right even when you're afraid.
班恩对丑丑格做的事 绝对是不义的
Bane's corruption of the Trogowogs is a travesty of justice.
小蝙蝠 就你所知 我家人和丑丑格几世纪前就是朋友
As you know, Batface, my family befriended Trogowogs centuries ago.
我们练的武术就是要保护他们
We perfected our martial arts to protect and defend them.
我不知道班恩是如何发现丑丑格的秘密
I don't know how Bane discovered the secret of the Trogowogs.
可能你会说梦话吧
Well, maybe you talked in your sleep? Ow!
蝙蝠侠 我们要赶快找到逃出去的方法
Batman, we've got to find a way to escape
我们就可以把丑丑格从班恩的手上救出来
so we can liberate the Trogowogs from Bane's rule.
哈啰 这笼子坚不可摧 多功能皮带又被没收了
Hello, escape-proof cage, confiscated utility belts.
- 我们没希望了 - 也不完全是这样
- We're all helpless here. - Not quite.
丧钟只顾着夺走我的多功能皮带
Deathstroke was so focused on getting my utility belt,
他却没看到能够帮我们离开这的工具
he overlooked the one thing that can get us out of here.
- 什么 - 他没看到那东西
- What? - He missed that?
所以这到底是什么
I say, what is that?
格格王子 这个啊 是我的蝙蝠积木拆解器
This, Prince Grungle, is my Bat-brick separator.
你看
Observe.
搞什么啊
Holy crowbar.
有这巨大的东西就能拆掉整个塔
That titanic tool could topple a tower.
我是不是曾经做过这件事
I did it again, didn't I?
专心点
Focus.
一旦我拆了这个地方 我们要赶快阻止班恩
Once I break through, we'll have to move quickly to stop Bane.
如果我们阻止不了他 就没有人可以阻止他的丑丑格军团
Because if we don't, no force on Earth will be able to stop his Trogowog army.
甚至连正义联盟都不行
Not even the Justice League.
两位男士人真好 第一次约会就准备晚餐
So kind of you gentlemen to provide dinner on our first date,
- 还特地把自己变成主餐 - 神奇女侠来了
- especially when you're the main course. - Mighty Aphrodite.
听到你们两位需要支援真是个好消息
It's a good thing you boys called for backup.
现在 请你老实说你对我的朋友做了什么
Now, tell me what you've done to my friends.
我使用特殊的植物荷尔蒙对你朋友下了毒
My special plant pheromones have intoxicated your friends
让他们屈服于我
and placed them under my control.
而下一个就是你了
And now I have you, too.
我们早就知道钢骨要你过来帮忙
We overheard Cyborg's pathetic call for your help.
我们一直都在等你
We've been waiting for you.
好玩的才正要开始
Now the real fun begins.
女士们先生们 欢迎钢骨 超人 还有神奇女侠
Ladies and gentlemen, Cyborgs, Supermen and Wonder Women.
欢迎来到哥谭市的最恶派对皇宫
Welcome to Gotham's preeminent party palace,
小丑奇趣屋
the Joker Fun House.
只有我们会觉得好玩吧
Fun for us, anyway.
小汤匙 你好坏
Oh, Spoony, you're so bad.
那汤匙会讲话
Is that a talking spoon?
我受够你的低级趣味了 小丑
I've had enough of this nonsense, Joker.
我不会再掉入你的陷阱
I'm not falling for any more tricks.
刚刚是有人说"掉入"吗
Did somebody say "falling"?
鲨鱼池
你们两个要再好好训练飞行时的紧急刹车
You two need to work on your emergency stops.
过了那关那这一关呢
Out of the water and into the frying pan.
放弃吧 企鹅人 我跟蝙蝠侠不一样 子弹对我…
Give it up, Penguin. Unlike Batman, bullets have no effect on...
那是什么东西啊
What is that?
是鱼吗
A fish?
我讨厌哥谭市 这里的罪犯真是太奇怪了
I hate Gotham City. Ugh. Its criminals are so weird.
超人别担心 我已经把鼻子塞住了
Don't worry, Superman, I've activated my internal nose plugs
也抑制住了想吐的欲望
and deactivated my gag reflex.
我会很快地把这些鱼给处理掉
I'll pluck that foul fish-flinging fowl.
我跟一般的企鹅不一样 我会飞喔
Unlike real penguins, this one can fly.
让他们尝尝恐惧瓦斯
Scarecrow, hit 'em with your fear gas.
- 你看这里好高好高 - 不 不 不
- Look how high up we are. - No, no, no.
我突然好怕高喔
I'm suddenly afraid of heights.
看来你们忘记系安全带了喔
Ha-ha! Looks like you forgot to buckle up.
太可惜了 因为这才刚开始
Too bad, because the ride's only just beginning.
- 哈啰 - 嘿 罗宾
- Hello. - Hey, Robin.
俏娇娃和我要去找乐子 我们要搭车出去
Starfire and I are about to finish off Giganta here in Metropolis.
不如你也一起来吧 一起去冒险 去披萨餐厅
How about you ditch the cave and join us for our next adventure, Pizza Pandemonium.
抱歉 野兽小子 我不能去
Sorry, Beast Boy, no can do.
什么 因为明天要上学吗
What? Because it's a school night?
还是是因为你其实是一只…
Or is it really because you're a...
弱鸡 我是一只弱鸡
Chicken, get it? Because I became a chicken?
帮我留点披萨
Save some pizza for me.
我必须留在哥谭市处理这个大问题
I have to stay here in Gotham and handle a big problem.
今天的空气充满活力啊 是吗
The air is just electric today, isn't it?
好像随时都会发生什么刺激的事
It's as though something exciting will happen at any moment.
- 真是让人兴奋 - 我也觉得很兴奋
- Scintillating. - I'm all a-tingle.
岸边安全 快走
The coast is clear. Come quickly.
谢谢你 老朋友
Thank you, old friend.
现在呢 我们要回去那个近乎无底的洞
What now? Find our way back up the nearly bottomless pit?
只要再爬几英里
Once we climb up a few miles,
我们就可以联络正义联盟 寻求他们的帮助
we should be able to signal the rest of the Justice League for help.
为什么打我
Ow! What was that for?
一本没有内容的书 是不会在图书馆里待太久的
A book with no pages is never overdue from the library.
是啊 什么意思啊
Right. What?
曼提斯女士的意思是说 班恩就只是个混混
Madame Mantis is saying that Bane is a bully.
面对混混的唯一方法就是正面迎击
And the only way to deal with a bully is to stand up to them.
我们从恐怖监狱逃出来的事被发现了
Our decampment from that ghastly Gulag has been discovered.
我们该怎么办
What shall we do?
格格 你要记住 所谓勇气跟感觉无关 而是取决于你的行动
Remember, Grungle, bravery isn't what you feel, it's what you do.
蝙蝠侠 听好了 逃跑是没用的
Batman, hear me. There is no escape for you.
是那个坏蛋 他变得好大啊
The tyrant. He's grown to gargantuan proportions.
快逃啊
Flee!
冷静点 格格王子
Calm yourself, Prince Grungle.
班恩只是使用 了心智石来投影自己的影像
Bane's merely using the Psyche Stone to project this image of himself.
出来面对 我也许可以放过你的朋友们
Turn yourself in and I may spare the lives of your friends.
格格王子 等等 这又没什么
Prince Grungle! Wait, it's nothing.
你错了 这是最可怕的
Wrong. It is something.
这是一个陷阱
It is a trap.
喔 喔 喔
Well, well, well.
是王子啊
The prince.
或者我应该说 旧王子 新料理
Or should I say, the former prince, future sushi.
我们已经找很久了
We've been searching forever.
我们不能再找下去了 得回到地面寻求支援
We should forget looking for him and get back to the surface world for reinforcements.
格格现在自己一个人 一定很害怕
Grungle is alone and he's frightened.
这奇怪的地底王国还有我们的世界 都会完蛋的
This whole weird underworld plus our world is doomed
如果班恩又把蝙蝠侠抓走的话
if Bane gets his hands on Bats again.
真是太可怕了
Now that's frightening.
太迟了 格格已经被抓走了
It's too late. Grungle has certainly been recaptured.
- 拜托 你怎么可能知道 - 蝙蝠侠
- Oh, come on, you can't possibly know... - Batman.
我这里有个朋友 想要跟你说说话
I have a friend here who'd like to talk to you.
不过呢 他好像话不多
On second thought, he's not much of a talker.
只是一直啜泣
More of a whimperer.
但是他啜泣也啜不了多久了
And he won't even be doing that much longer.
我们等等见
I will see you soon.
你不能回去救他 这样就会正中他的目的
You can't go back for him. You're playing right into his hands.
但是我们也不能不管格格啊
But we can't leave Grungle for dead.
你离开吧 我来想办法救格格
You go, I'll try to free Grungle.
他拿我没辙的 没有人可以打击我这个老石头
He can't get the secret from me. No one can crack this old nut.
不 还有一个办法可以阻止班恩
No, there's only one way to stop Bane.
什么办法
How?
就是告诉他禁忌的攻击
By giving him the secret of the forbidden move.
这个氪星石制的浴缸让人虚软无力
This Kryptonite bathtub is strangely soothing.
一定是因为毒藤女又放了些植物进去
Must be those vegetables Poison Ivy added to this soup we're sitting in.
先别说我们会不会死 我现在觉得还蛮平静的
Despite our certain demise I just feel so calm right now.
我觉得一定是汤匙害的
I blame the spoon.
- 为什么 - 因为它是汤匙
- Why's that? - It's a soup spoon.
小汤匙 很快地 他们就会慢慢煮沸成为水蒸气
And very soon now, Spoony, they'll be boiled away into vapors.
然后我们就可以彻底摆脱这些烦人的超级英雄
And we'll be rid of half of the world's most annoying superheroes.
然后就可以尽情捣蛋了
Emphasis on the soup.
他快不行了
He's breaking.
我一定要战胜这块石头
Must fight stone.
跳舞吧
Dance.
跳舞
Dance!
他想要跳舞
He wants to dance?
丧钟 这心灵就像是长得像大脑形状的皮纳塔
The mind is like a brain-shaped piñata, Deathstroke.
只要我们打破它的外壳 记忆的糖果就会掉出来
As we beat it to shreds, the hard candies of random memory spills
这一切都是注定好的
on the lawn of destiny.
增加心智石的能量
Increase the power.
这个攻击并不会致死
This move does not kill.
但是后果会更严重
It is worse.
他会使身体变成碎片 但是依然活着
It splits the body into pieces, but life remains.
真是太可怕了
That's horrible.
我知道 所以才会被称之为禁忌的攻击
I know. That's why it's called the forbidden move.
那为什么要教我这个
Then why show me it at all?
嘿 我是老师 我来决定要教什么
Hey, who's the master here?
现在呢 很简单
Now, it's very simple.
你要先把手弄成C的形状
You just form your hand into a C-shape
这样你的气就会集中成一个圆形能量
and will all your chi into one tiny stud of power.
真是不可思议
Incredible.
现在把能量瞄准 扔向人形积木体
Now, hurl the stud of power toward the dummy of practice.
终于 我学会了禁忌的攻击
Finally, I have the forbidden move!
我们在笑什么
What are we laughing at?
我不知道 我想他只是创造出一个很好笑的环境吧
I don't know, I think he's just creating a fun work environment.
完蛋了 他们什么都知道了
It is done. They now know all.
神奇女侠 钢骨 我很开心能与你们共事
Wonder Woman, Cyborg, it was my pleasure to fight alongside you.
我也是
Me, too.
不 是蝙蝠侠 他回来了
Oh, no, it's Batman. He's back.
冷静点 只是蝙蝠侠的小跟班
Pull yourself together. It's only the Brat Wonder.
没错
That's right.
而我想你一定想知道 我要怎么打破你的热水缸
And I wonder how you're going to like me shutting down your hot tub of horror.
你这该死的小鬼
You butting-in bird boy.
真希望能跟你们多聊聊 但是我要去救我的朋友
Wish I could stay and chat, but I have some friends to save.
该出来了喔 正义联盟 游泳课结束了
Out of the pool, Justice League. Adult swim is over.
在他们重新聚集前快走
Come on, before they regroup.
真是太可笑了
Right in the funny bone.
我刚才好像做了个奇怪的梦
I just had the strangest dream.
有个热热的浴缸 还有神奇女侠
There was a hot tub and Wonder Woman.
- 还有… - 现在没时间讲这个了 钢骨
- And...? - No time for that now, Cyborg.
快走吧
Up, up and away.
你们看 正义联盟已经走了
Look, the Justice League is running away.
哥谭市是我们的了
Gotham is ours.
毒藤女的汤让我手脚吱吱响
Poison Ivy's soup made my servos squeak.
- 谢谢你来救我们 罗宾 - 你真的是个神奇小子
- Thanks for coming to save us, Robin. - You really are the Boy Wonder.
如果你一开始就照我说的去做 我就不用去救你们了
I wouldn't have had to save you if you had listened to me in the first place.
再跟我多说一点
Tell me about it.
不然蝙蝠侠回来 他会给我那个表情
And when Batman gets back, he's going to give me "the look."
因为他交给我一个美好的城市 但我把它搞砸了
Because he loaned me a perfectly good city and I broke it.
喔对 我知道你说的表情
Oh, yes, I know that look.
好啦 我会帮你处理眼前这一切
Okay, I'm going to help you clean up this mess.
但是呢 虽然我们的罪犯都没有超能力
But just because some of our criminals don't have superpowers
那并不代表他们就不危险
doesn't mean they're not super-dangerous.
你说得没错
You got that right.
他们是最难预测的 最邪恶的 最危险的坏蛋
They're unpredictable, diabolical, dangerous villains.
只有一个方式可以阻止他们
And there's only one way to stop them.
什么方式
What way is that?
蝙蝠侠的方式
The Bat-way.
一个接一个 请跟着队伍移动
One to a customer. Keep the line moving, please.
就是这样
That's it.
让心智石告诉你 要如何使用
Let the Psyche Stone fill your little minds with the deadly
禁忌的攻击
forbidden move.
我说啊 那个禁忌的攻击知道了后 其实也没那么难
Oh! I say, the forbidden move is jolly easy once you know the secret.
对对对 快走
Yes, yes, move along.
丧钟跑去哪了
Where did Deathstroke sneak off to?
丧钟 你到底想怎样
Deathstroke, what do you want?
他只想做一件事
The only thing he's ever wanted.
没错 就是证明她是错的
That's right. To prove she's wrong.
证明我比你还要强
To prove I'm better than you.
没有什么强不强的
There was no "better."
我只是教给准备好的人 而你还没有准备好 钟丧
Only those that are ready to learn. And you are not ready, Strokedeath.
- 是丧钟 - 等等
- It's Deathstroke. - Wait a minute.
蝙蝠侠说 你们以前在学校时是好朋友
Batman said you were best friends at school.
- 等等 你说什么 - 我们之间也是敌人
- Wait, what? - We were also worst enemies.
以前班上只有我们两个
There were only two of us in the class.
这是你的错
This is on your head.
你明明就比较喜欢他
You preferred him over me.
而且只是因为他的面具 做得比我好
Just because you thought his mask was better than mine.
我还是看不懂那个紫色橘色的东西
I never got the purple/orange thing.
- 是比较好啊 - 跟你的比起来是没错啊
- It is better. - There's really not much to yours.
我无法操控你的命运 只有你自己可以 钟丧
It is not me who determined your destiny. It was only ever you, Strokedeath.
我告诉过你 我是丧钟
Argh! I told you, it's Deathstroke.
不 你选择了他
No, you picked him over me.
而你错了
And you were wrong.
而我现在也学会了禁忌的攻击 我要告诉你谁是才最强的
Now that I know the forbidden move, I'll show you who's really the best.
这根本不公平
That's hardly fair.
蝙蝠侠才刚刚受尽折磨 你现在要跟他打架
Batman is zonked out of his ears and you want to fight him?
话讲够了吧
Enough talk.
来吧 蝙蝠侠 战斗吧
Come, Batman. Fight me.
证明你有曼提斯女士的所有技能
Prove that you were worthy of Madame Mantis' skills.
放弃吧 丧钟
Give it up, Deathstroke.
有好的理由战斗 才能赢得真正的胜利
True victory only comes when you fight for a good cause.
我战斗的理由再好不过
I fight for the best cause of all.
我是为了我自己
Myself.
你已经输了
Then you have already lost.
我来告诉你谁才是输家
I'll show you who's lost.
你成功了 你打败我了
You've done it. You've bested me.
有了禁忌的攻击方式 整个世界都是你的了
With the power of the forbidden move, the world is yours.
你再也不需要去争夺什么
You'll never be challenged again.
现在 做个了结吧 老朋友
Now, finish it, old friend.
不 我做不到
No, I can't do it.
这样太容易了
It's just too easy.
我嫉妒你 蝙蝠侠 你拥有所有的一切
I envy you, Batman, for being everything I'm not.
这些年你明明可以使用禁忌的攻击来打败我
You could have used the forbidden move against me all these years.
但是你没有
But you didn't.
你就是这样高尚的人
You're just too darned honorable.
你不该被这样的攻击方式给毁灭
You don't deserve to be destroyed by such a despicable technique.
- 谢谢你 史莱德 - 都结束了
- Thank you, Slade. - It is done.
- 她解开了 - 等等
- Uh, she's free? - Wait a minute.
原来只要你想解开绳子 随时都可以啊
You could have gotten out of those ropes anytime you wanted.
你的课程已经结束了 钟丧
Your lesson is completed, Strokedeath.
你已经学到了禁忌攻击的真谛
You have now earned the knowledge of the forbidden move.
我不懂 我并没有使用禁忌的攻击啊
I don't understand. I just failed to use the forbidden move.
- 我想我也不会去使用 - 所以我说你已经知道了
- I don't think I'll ever use it. - That is how I know you are ready for it.
所有的战争 都应该是荣耀的
All have the potential to be an honorable warrior,
包含所有的攻击方式 也都应该是荣耀的
but only through an act of honor could it be attained.
你说得对 曼提斯女士
You... You're right, Madame Mantis.
那是当然
Of course.
- 曼提斯女士永远是对的 - 但是一切都太晚了
- Madame Mantis is always right. - But it's too late.
我做了太多错事
I've done everything wrong.
班恩的军队已经准备好要攻击世界了
Bane's army is ready to invade the world above
没有人可以阻止得了他
and there is nothing I can do to stop it.
也许一个人是不行
Maybe you can't do it alone.
但是我们可以一起对抗 好同学
But we can do it together, classmate.
这是我的荣幸
It would be an honor.
博物馆
哥谭市之花
现在来欢迎哥谭市新上任的警察局长 小汤匙
And now, newly appointed Police Commissioner Spoony
让我们来看一下 哥谭市的一些新规则
shall review my suggestions for the new rules of Gotham City.
赦免所有罪犯
Amnesty for all criminals?
同意
Approved.
把所有超级英雄都关起来
Imprisonment for all superheroes?
同意同意
Double approved.
喔耶
Hooray!
小汤匙局长 你最棒了
Commissioner Spoony, oh, you're the greatest.
敲门敲门
Knock, knock.
是谁
Who's there?
我是…
Ima.
你是谁
Ima who?
我是来送你回阿卡姆的 那才是你要待的地方 小丑
Ima send you right back to Arkham where you belong, Joker.
我被敲门的笑话给骗了
Oh, knocked out by a knock-knock joke.
而且还是超人的笑话
From the Big Blue Bore Scout.
还真是好笑
Now that's a laugh.
我的小汤匙呢
Where's Spoony?
小丑啊 小汤匙不会跟你一起回阿卡姆疯人院的
Spoony won't be joining you back in Arkham, Joker.
希望你会喜欢阿卡姆提供的麦片粥 但是要用手吃喔
Hope you enjoy eating the Asylum oatmeal with your hands.
你们听着
Underlings.
是时候该拿回属于我们的地方了 成为地面上的主宰者
It is time for us to take our rightful place as the rulers of the surface world.
很明显 一定是我来当主宰者 而你们负责执行命令
Frankly, it'll be me doing most of the ruling and you doing most of the oppressing.
我们都有我们该做的事 这就是人生
We all have our jobs to do. C'est la vie.
现在出发吧 去完成我们的使命
Now, go forth and fulfill your destiny.
班恩
Bane!
我必须要说要到地面上去 我觉得很兴奋
I must say, I'm so excited to get to the surface world.
是因为要去打仗吗
Because of all the conquering?
不是 其实呢 我比较期待晒太阳
No, frankly, I'm just looking forward to getting a tan.
几千年以来 你的族人们都可以靠着自己的力量
For countless millennia your family could have ordered a wave of Trogowog might
去横扫地面上的军队
to sweep the armies of the surface world aside.
而你却什么都没做
But you did nothing.
那就只好靠班恩的力量了
It took Bane to make something of you.
我们是爱好和平的人群
We were a peaceful people
是你用卑鄙的破坏野心来控制我们
until you poisoned us with your vile destructiveness.
所谓和平就是一片薯片掉在下着雨的路上
Peace is like a stale potato chip left out in the rain
被一群女学生踩过
and stepped on by a group of schoolgirls.
你活该如此 你就像是只胆小的狗
You deserve your fate, you cowering dog.
你的族人们在我的命令下
Your people marching on my orders
进攻的画面 会是我杀死你时眼前的最后一幕
will be the final thing you see before I destroy you.
嗯 班恩 我想应该会比你好一点
Well, better that than you, Bane.
你带着那个面具看得到东西吗
You're hard to look at even with the mask on.
- 是谁那么大胆 - 是我们
- Who dares? - We dare.
你以为我会输给两只小英雄吗
Do you expect me to lose to two tiny heroes?
不 我们觉得你会输给一只中等体型的英雄
No, we expect you to lose to one medium-sized hero.
你看我真是太没礼貌了 我应该要给你们椅子坐的
How rude of me. I should have offered you a chair.
不
No.
是时候该来点控制术了
Time for a little rodent control.
- 我们要进隧道了 - 希望不要有人传讯息给我
- Oh, we're going into a tunnel. - I do hope no one tries to text me.
这里就够远了
That's far enough.
- 你看 第一个上来受死的 - 为了班恩的荣耀
- Oh, look, our first victims. - For the glory of Bane!
可能会比我们想象中的还要困难
This is going to be harder than we thought.
也许没有你想的那么难
Maybe not as hard as you think.
什么 怎么会
What? How?
透过这个 我可以自由召唤蝙蝠工具车
I took the liberty of summoning my Bat-drill with this.
他可以一直挖洞
It's been digging ever since.
我猜可能八成会用上
I suspected it might come in handy.
那个巨大的东西撞上我 还害我转了一圈
That ghastly machine gave me a turn.
摧毁它
Destroy it!
- 这些人就是不肯轻易放弃 - 我们也是啊
- These little guys don't give up easily. - Neither do we.
我们再厉害 也无法打赢整支军队
As good as we are, we can't defeat an entire army.
现在是不行
Not at this rate.
被解开了
Oh, emancipated.
但我现在该怎么办
But what do I do now?
是你该做决定的时候了
That is for you to decide.
什么
What?
放开她 你这个坏蛋
Unhand her, you cur.
小王子要勇敢起来啦
Oh, so the little prince has grown a backbone?
让我来帮帮你吧
Allow me to help you with that.
我击败了你的父亲 我也会击败你
I destroyed your father and I will destroy you.
那我就会像个国王一样光荣的死去
Then I shall die like a king.
我还有一招
I have one more card to play.
好的
Okay.
如果你有需要的话再跟我说
I'll just be here if you need me.
丑丑格 听我说
Trogowogs, listen to me.
是坏蛋班恩控制了你们的心智 利用来完成他的邪恶计划
The criminal Bane has altered your minds to use you for his own evil ends.
但是你们一定可以战胜他的 要坚定你们的心智
But you can fight it. Assert your free will.
我知道你们办得到 我知道你们会选择和平
I know you can do it. I know you will choose peace.
谢谢你的解说
Thanks awfully.
但是我觉得 我们还是应该要把你们变成碎片
But I think instead we shall obliterate you completely.
- 你也这样觉得吗 - 你知道我和你一样
- Don't you think we should? - You know I do.
不会有任何疼痛的感觉 你还有遗言吗
Just to show there's no hard feelings, have you any final words?
只有一个字…
Just one...
跳 跳 跳
Batoosie, Batoosie, Batoosie.
我以前没看过这种事
I didn't see this coming.
- 谢天谢地 - 嘿 你看格格
- Oh, thank goodness. - Hey, look at Grungle go.
因为他太小只 班恩根本碰不到他
He's so small, Bane can't even touch him.
是啊 格格王子已经通过测验
Yes, Prince Grungle has passed his test.
现在只要让其他的丑丑格见到这一慕
If only the other Trogowogs could see him now.
喔 对 心智石
Yeah, of course. The Psyche Stone.
- 夜翼 - 我知道 来吧
- Nightwing. - Got it, let's do it.
孩子 这边 稳住你的步伐 拿着这根棍子
Here, kid. Walk softly and carry a big stick.
那只是根小棍子 而我巨大无比
That is a very small stick and I am a very big man.
不
No!
班恩 你玩完了
You're finished, Bane.
我可能无法巨大化 但是我还是最强的
I may no longer be grande but you will find I am still supreme.
我说啊 丑丑格在格斗比赛里不再是只有挨打的份了
I say, Prince Grungle is certainly no slouch in the fisticuffs department.
班恩啊 被打趴得像手帕一样
Bane, however folded like a cloth napkin.
真是太精彩了
Good show.
再一次 再一次
Encore, encore.
我知道了
Oh, I see.
你知道心智石一定会从你的心灵偷走禁忌的攻击
You knew the Psyche Stone would eventually steal the forbidden move from your mind.
所以你直接加了一段舞蹈
So you simply added a mental suggestion to dance.
只要我说"跳" 他们就会开始跳舞
Activated when I said the word "Batoosie."
小蝙蝠 干得好
Well played, Batface.
不错喔
Not bad.
虽然跟武术无关 但是做得很好
Not exactly martial arts, but not bad.
我只有一个问题 为什么钟丧没一起跳舞
My only question, why is Strokedeath not dancing?
曼提斯女士 尽管我尚未完成你的授业
Madame Mantis, even with your incomplete teaching,
但是我成为了世界上最厉害的佣兵
I have become the world's greatest mercenary.
只有一件事情 丧钟不会也不可能做
But there is still one thing Deathstroke cannot and will not do.
那就是跳舞
Dance.
什么
What?
难怪你坏成这样
No wonder you're so bad.
跳舞对心灵十分有帮助
Dancing is good for the soul.
你回来我的道场 我也有教舞蹈喔
You come back to my dojo. It is also Madame Mantis' dance academy.
禁忌的攻击都已经被消除了
The forbidden move has been erased.
是啊 这是最后一批
Yep, that's the last of them.
这样就可以回到他们的小小洞穴 继续他们和平友爱的生活
Back to their little peace-loving lives in their little secret cave.
蝙蝠女 可以打扰你一下吗
Batgirl... A moment?
白马王子来了 我要先离开了
Here comes Prince Charming. I've got to go...
去别的地方
Do something...
做点其他的事
Somewhere...
我永远感谢你
You have my eternal gratitude.
你救了我和我的族人们
You saved both my people and myself.
嘿 是你救了你的国家
Hey, you saved your kingdom,
而且我觉得呢 你的族人们都十分认同
and from the sound of things, I think your people agree.
蝙蝠女 你既漂亮又勇敢
Batgirl, you're beautiful, you're brave,
而且你还激发我成为勇敢的人
and what's more, you inspire me to be brave.
我只想跟你走 永远待在你身边
I want nothing more than to go with you and stay by your side forever.
格格王子你真好
Oh, that is so sweet, Prince Grungle.
你是个好人 但是…
Um, you are really wonderful, but...
不巧的是 我现在是国王了
Unfortunately, I am now king,
我不能依着我的想法来做事
and my needs are always secondary to those of my subjects.
唉 我必须待在这里
Alas, here I must remain.
至于班恩呢 他会被关在地牢里 永永远远
As for Bane, he will now reside in our dungeon, forever captive.
但我的心不会
Not unlike my heart.
别说了
Oh, stop.
丧钟 现在你找回了你的荣誉感
Well, Deathstroke, now that your honor has been restored...
不 小蝙蝠 一起打击罪犯
Look. Batface, our little class reunion
是不错 但是我们不可能是朋友
has been just great, but we're still not friends.
等到下一次见面 我们就在同样的水平上
And when next we meet, it will be as true equals.
这样好吗
That went well.
夜翼 他虽然无法当英雄
He may not be a hero, Nightwing,
但是丧钟曾经踩着光荣的步伐
but Deathstroke once again walks the path of honor.
这样就够了
And that may be enough.
欢迎回家 蝙蝠侠
被小鬼给耍了 我不会忘记这样的耻辱
Outsmarted by an oversized boy scout. I'll never live it down.
永远 永远不会
Never, never, never!
嗯 这样就结束了
Well, that's the last of them.
我们可以在围墙后进行严格的管控
Behind the walls of a completely reliable mental health facility.
也管不了多久了 你看
And not a moment too soon. Look.
嗨 大家好
Hi, guys.
- 罗宾 你听我说 - 我知道啦
- Robin, listen... - I know.
别担心
Don't worry.
其实真的没有必要让蝙蝠侠知道…
There's really no reason to let Batman know how...
超人是怎么放走阿卡姆里面的罪犯
How Superman released all the inmates from Arkham Asylum?
小丑是怎么用汤匙戏弄超人吗
The Joker outsmarted Superman with a spoon?
那些大坏蛋是怎么差点毁了哥谭市
How the super-criminals almost succeeded in the wrecking of the city?
对对对 你们说的没错
Yes, yes, that's it exactly.
蝙蝠侠 黑暗骑士 欢迎你回家
Batman. Welcome home, Dark Knight.
我不在时有任何麻烦事吗
Any trouble while I was away?
没有
No.
我是说 你知道的 每件事都再平凡不过了
Well, I mean, you know, I mean, nothing out of the ordinary.
我没办法说谎
I cannot tell a lie!
小丑用汤匙戏弄我
Joker outsmarted me with a spoon
害我放走了阿卡姆的所有罪犯
and tricked me into releasing Arkham's criminals
他们差一点毁了整个哥谭市
who almost succeeded in wrecking Gotham City.
是真的 哥谭市的罪犯是出奇的怪异
It's true, Gotham's criminals are an entirely new level of weird.
他们还差点把我熬成汤
They almost turned us into soup.
别担心 每件事我都一清二楚 除了那只汤匙
Don't worry, I anticipated every part of that, except the spoon.
不管怎样 现在城市又安全了
All that matters now is that the city is safe once again
多亏了你们四个
thanks to the four of you.
罗宾 你把他们从小丑奇趣屋救出来那段真是太棒了
Excellent rescue at Joker's Fun House, Robin.
孩子 做得好
Great job, kid.
在我还是罗宾的时候 也有过不少成就
I set a pretty high standard when I was Robin,
但是你这次真的做得很漂亮
but you're taking it to a whole new level.
谢啦 夜翼 谢啦 蝙蝠侠
Thanks, Nightwing. Thanks, Batman.
但是你是怎么知道在小丑奇趣屋发生的事
But how did you know what happened at Joker's Fun House?
因为我是…
Because I'm...
小蝙蝠
Batface.
又一次完成了英雄式的冒险
And so ends another heroic adventure.
正义得到了伸张
Justice has been served
而我们最爱的哥谭市 又再一次的安全了
and our beloved Gotham City is once again safe.
一切都要感谢…
Thanks to...